With the burger ingredient prepared,
Hazrlanan burger bileeni ile.
let's move on to the burger component
Hadi hamburger bileeni ile devam edelim.
and I will try this in a functional form again,
Ve bunu tekrar fonksiyonel bir biimde deneyeceim.
name the function burger, receive some props and there again, I will use curly braces so that I can also
lev burgeri adn baz sahne alm olarak adlandrn ve yine J harfi dnmeden nce
add some javascript logic before returning jsx.
baz javascript mant ekleyebilmem iin kvrck ayralar kullanacam.
For now, all I'll do there is return some jsx though
imdilik, yapaca JS X geriye dnleri var.
but we will revisit this component to enhance it and conditionally render something else later.
Ancak, onu gelitirmek ve koullu olarak daha sonra baka bir ey yaratmak iin bu bileeni tekrar gzden geireceiz.
For now, let's import react from react because we well use jsx and let's export a default, the
aktive edelim, nk j'yi X olarak iyi kullanyoruz ve elbette bir burger fonksiyonunu bir varsaylana aktaralm.
burger function of course.
imdilik, reaktif hareketi tekrar
Now what is the
imdi orada ne var.
jsx I want to export. The jsx should simply use this burger ingredient component
James x Ben kendi JS X vermek istiyorum sadece bu Bergere bileen bileen kullanmanz gerekir.
we created, actually multiple of them but I also want to wrap everything in a div.
Onlarn ounu aslnda yaratyoruz ama her eyi bir div iine sarmak istiyorum.
So here I deliberately use a div because I want to give this wrapper which this burger component essentially
Yani ben burada kasten bir div kullanyorum, nk Bergere bileenini yapan bu sarmalayc aslnda
is, it's a wrapper around all the ingredients,
tm malzemelerin etrafnda bir sarc gibi.
I want to give it some styling to define the width and height of our burger. So for that,
demek iin Bruer'imizin geniliini ve yksekliini tanmlamak iin biraz stil vermek istiyorum.
I'll add a new file
Yeni bir d ekleyeceim.
the burger.css file and there I'll add up burger css class.
Bergere nokta C S S dosyas ve hepsi snf olarak burger Seer's' ekliyor.
Not I want to give this class a width of
Bu snfa nefes alacak biri deil.
let's say 100% and the margin of auto
Diyelim ki yzde 100 ve otomatik kenar boluu.
but I want to limit the height to 250px and feel free to choose a different height
Ancak ykseklii 250 piksel ile snrlamak ve farkl bir ykseklik semekten ekinmemek istiyorum.
of course, it's just something I think will look OK.
Elbette sadece grneceini dndm bir ey var.
I will set the overflow to scroll so that even if we build a bigger burger then the 250px, we can
Tamay ayarlayacam, bylece daha byk bir burger, daha sonra 250 piksel ina etsek bile basite kaydrabiliriz ve
simply scroll it and we don't have it overlap or cut off because we do limit the height here.
st ste getirme veya kesme ilemine tabi tutmamakta, nk burada ykseklii snrlyoruz.
If we would limit the height and we build a very big burger, it would somehow take up our entire page
burger ina edersek, bir ekilde tm sayfamz veya daha fazlasn alacaz ve doru grnmyor.
or more than that and that wouldn't look great.
Eer ykseklii snrlamazsak ve ok byk bir
I will also add text-align center to center everything and font-weight should be bold,
Ayrca, her eyi ortalamak iin metni hizalama metni ekleyeceim ve nerede ina edileceini bulacam.
we don't print any text yet but we'll do so in the future.
Henz herhangi bir metin basmyoruz, ancak gelecekte yapacaz.
I'll also set the font-size to 1.2rem, this simply is a unit in case you don't know which scales
Ayrca yaz tipi boyutunu bir Hollandaca'dan R'ye ayarlayn. E. M. Bu, kullanc tarafndan seilen varsaylan yaz
it based on the default font-size the user selected.
tipi boyutuna bal olarak hangi lein temelini oluturduunu bilmiyorsanz bir birim olarak basite.
So this is the layout I want to use,
Bu yzden kullanmak istediim dzen bu.
it's the mobile layout though.
Ancak mobil dzen.
I now want to create a media query here where I check if we have a screen width of let's set minimum
ettiim bir medya sorgusu oluturmak istiyorum ve bu Bergere tabii ki kelime oluturduundan nemlidir.
1000px and that's important because the burger of course is built logically.
imdi burada bir minimum 1000 piksellik bir ekrana sahip olup olmadm kontrol
If we have a minimum height of 700px,
En az 700 piksel yksekliimiz varsa.
if that's the case, then my burger class will be tweaked and I won't set the width to 100% but
Durum byleyse, Bergere snfm sktracak ve ei yzde 100'e, ancak 2
to 700px and the height to 600.
700 piksele ve ykseklii 600'e ayarlamayacam.
I will also add another media query where I will check if the min-width is 500px so a bit smaller,
Ayrca, menwith'in 500 piksel kadar biraz daha kk olup olmadn ve min ykseklii 400 ve
and if the min height is 401px and if that's the case, I want to take 450px as width
bir piksel olup olmadn kontrol edecek baka bir medya sorgusu ekleyecek ve bu durumda 450 piksel
and 400px as height. And finally to also handle devices which are not that wide but pretty tall,
genilik ve 400 piksel ykseklik olarak almak istiyorum ve sonunda tm l beyaz ama olduka uzun olmayan cihazlar ele alacaz.
put in other word, in portrait mode,
Portre modunda bir kelime yaz.
I want to have a media rule for a minimum width of 500px but a maximum height of 400
En az be yz piksel geniliinde, ancak en fazla 400 ykseklikte bir duvar resmi istiyorum.
and there, I want to make sure that the width is 350 and the height is 300px.
Ve orada 350 ve ykseklii 300 piksel olduundan emin olmak istiyorum.
So these are just some media queries to ensure that the burger looks good on as many viewports as possible,
Yani bunlar, burgerin olabildiince ok bak asna iyi geldiinden emin olmak iin yalnzca baz medya sorular.
as always feel free to tweak this to your needs
Her zaman olduu gibi bunu kendi ihtiyalarnza gre ayarlayabilirsiniz.
if you feel like it doesn't look that good on your device.
Cihaznzda iyi grnmediini dnyorsanz.
Now enough of css
imdi C S S. yeterince.
let's go back to the burger and let's import the css
Burger'e geri dnelim ve hadi D.'yi alalm. C. Var.
classes we just added, store it in that classes object thereafter.
Daha sonra dzenlediimiz snflar bundan sonra o cam nesnede sakland.
Let's import them from the burger css file and let's attach them to that wrapping div with class
Onlar burger CSSA dosyasndan ie aktaralm ve bunlar snf adyla sarmalamaya
name and the class always is burger,
ve bunlarn daima Asperger'a ekleyelim.
the media query doesn't matter for that.
Medya Cuore bunun iin nemli deil.
Now we can start adding ingredients inside of that burger,
imdi o burgerin iine ierikler eklemeye balayabiliriz.
so I will import burger ingredient from the BurgerIngredient folder and there, the burger ingredients
Bylece Bergere bileenini Burger King blgesi klasrnden alacam ve burger ierikli CSSA dosyas var ve
css file and now we can simply use it as a self-closing component like that, burger ingredient but
imdi sadece Burgert bileeni gibi kendi kendine kapanan bir bileen olarak kullanabilirsiniz, ancak bir
keep in mind, we have to define a type.
tr tanmlamamz gerektiini unutmayn.
The type can be a string
Tr bir dize olabilir.
actually it can't be a string,
Aslnda bir ip olamaz.
it has to be a string,
Bir dize olmal.
we implement that prop type checking, and I will start with a bread-top here
Pervane tip kontroln uyguluyoruz ve burada bir ekmek balayacaz.
so I guess it makes sense to have this at
Bu yzden sanrm bu ii yapmak mantkl.
well the top. At the bottom
En alttan st.
you're never going to guess it, I'll add bread-bottom. And now in between let's add two more ingredients, maybe
Bir saat iinde krmz dudakta tahmin edeceini asla dnmyorsunuz, belki biraz daha
some cheese and below that, meat.
iki peynir ve etin altnda etler ekleyelim.
Now with that,
imdi ller.
I got my burger component which should render a burger with bread, meat and cheese.
Ekmek eti ve peynirle burger yapacak burger bileenim var.
Now let's implement this and let's simply render this burger.
imdi bunu uygulamaya balayalm ve bu hamur iini yapalm.
We're exporting it already
Zaten ihra ediyoruz.
so now we can go to our burger builder container and there, replace this dummy div with our burger.
imdi burger Boulder konteynerine gidebiliriz ve bu Dammy lmnn yerini burgerimiz alyor.
So I'll import burger from
Yani burgeri ie aktar.
and now, we have to go up to the source level, then into components, into burger and import burger.js
Ve imdi kaynak seviyesine kmalyz burger ve ithal burger bileenlerine gitmeliyiz.
and now replace that div with our self-closing burger component.
J. S. ve imdi bu fark kendi kendine kapanan burger bileenimizle deitir.
Let's save this, save everything and let's reload the page and you should see this burger, in case your
eyi kaydetmek iin kaydedelim ve sayfay yeniden ykleyelim ve stiliniz kapalysa bu burgeri grmelisiniz.
styling is off,
Bu bilgiyi her
make sure to compare your css code of that component with mine.
Bu bileenin CSX kodunu benimkiyle karlatrdnzdan emin olun.
You should see that it also looks OK if you shrink and resize the page, again
Sayfay kltp yeniden boyutlandrrsanz, yine de iyi grnyor olduunu grmelisiniz.
feel free to adjust this css to fit all possible sizes you might need.
htiyacnz olan tm olas boyutlar sdrmak iin CSSA'y adaletsiz hissedin.
That's the burger,
te burger.
that's great.
Bu harika.
Not so great is that
Bu o kadar da harika deil.
everything about this burger is in the end hard coded.
Bu burger ile ilgili her ey sonunda kodlanm sert.
We're using components but we're not able to change this burger dynamically and we're not even rendering
Bileenler kullanyoruz, ancak bu burgeri dinamik olarak deitiremiyoruz ve bunu dinamik
this dynamically.
olarak oluturmuyoruz.
So let's start by managing the ingredients via state and rendering the burger dynamically in the next
yleyse neden bir devlet ynetmek ve sonraki derslerde hamburger'i dinamik olarak hazrlayarak
lectures.
balayalm.